It's a merry Muppet Christmas with Fozzie and friends!
A Muppet Family Christmas is a family, comedy,
music film directed by Peter Harris.
Fozzie Bear surprises his mother on Christmas Eve by bringing the
entire Muppet gang to her farm to celebrate the holidays.
Doc and his dog Sprocket, who had planned a quiet Christmas, end up joining
the Muppets in their holiday activities and preparations.
The Sesame Street and Fraggle Rock regulars join the festivities, but to Kermit's dismay,
the only one missing is Miss Piggy, who has been caught in a snowstorm.
Kermit the Frog / Rowlf the Dog / Dr. Teeth / Swedish Chef /
Waldorf / Ernie / Self, played by Jim Henson.
Miss Piggy / Fozzy Bear / Animal / Sam the Eagle / Bert /
Grover / Cookie Monster, played by Frank Oz.
Gonzo / Dr. Bunsen Honeydew / Zoot / Beauregard /
Boober Fraggle, played by Dave Goelz.
Robin the Frog / Camilla the Chicken / Floyd Pepper / Lew Zealand / Pops / The
Count / Gobo Fraggle / Herry Monster, played by Jerry Nelson.
Scooter / Janice / Statler / Beaker / Gladys the Cow / Two-Headed
Monster / Snowman (voice), played by Richard Hunt.
Mokey Fraggle (voice), played by Kathryn Mullen.
A Muppet Family Christmas is a Christmas musical
television special starring Jim Henson's Muppets.
It first aired on December 16, 1987, on the ABC
television network in the United States.
Its teleplay was conceived by longtime Muppet writer
Jerry Juhl, and directed by Peter Harris.
This television special was filmed at 9 Channel Nine Court in Toronto, Ontario.
The special features various Muppets from The Muppet Show,
Sesame Street, Fraggle Rock, and Muppet Babies.
It also stars Gerry Parkes as Doc from the North American wraparound segments of
Fraggle Rock, and Henson as himself in a cameo appearance at the end.
In the plot, the Muppets surprise Fozzie Bear's mother with a Christmas visit
to her farmhouse, unaware of her planned getaway to Malibu.
Due to licensing issues with songs featured in A Muppet Family Christmas,
some scenes have been cut from subsequent home media releases.
The film explores themes of holiday, christmas
party, snowstorm, puppet, blizzard.
The tone is lighthearted.